we're gonna start today's episode where
we left off last episode i have been
afking at my very inefficient gold farm
which is why it's taken
an entire evening
to get just a small amount of gold so
i've been steadily crafting these into
bars and feeding them to the pigs which
have then been giving me a lot of stuff
so check it out i mean the black stone's
probably the best example we've got
nearly three double chests full and the
reason i've been doing this is because
this is going to be a huge bit of stock
for the barge expansion that we are
working on at the moment but since this
is a bit of a long-term project it's
something that's going to have to happen
predominantly off-camera especially as
you can't make any content out of being
afk unless you're mumbo jumbo so we're
heading back man i've i did not miss
this tunnel we are currently heading
back to the shopping district where we
need to make more progress on our mini
game as the clock is ticking to get it
finished to discover who's going to win
the turf war there we go
our still very wingless
airplane
do you know what i actually saw a
comment which i loved and potentially
could be something that i'd change about
this design
so what they said was why don't i make
it an airplane that's like crashing or
like you know something's on fire and
that's why you have to jump out of the
plane so if i can do that i will but
sorry
can we just
all agree
that i was gliding very slowly but
goodness i was in here i feel like that
did not deserve a death
so the first thing that i want to do
is lay out the square that we're going
to make and we're going to start the
biggest grinding dig you've ever seen
we've got to go all the way down to
bedrock so this is this is not gonna be
particularly enjoyable but it's
something we gotta do
so let's get into another hole digging
as if i haven't done enough hole digging
this series
okay let's go
[Applause]
i've been digging for so long i'm now in
my christmas skin if this video is a
little bit late and by a little bit i
mean by a few days
i think you realize why this was nine
straight hours of building and someone's
someone's written hello in there and i
think we can all agree it was nine hours
wasted because this is one ugly hole but
don't worry i have a plan you see over
here i have a nice gradient to surround
it that's right even more work for me so
i've gathered up some blocks and
starting from the bottom i'm basically
going to layer this up bit by bit chunk
by chunk until we have a really nice
looking inverted dirt cube it should
look like
man i realized
for the sake
of 60 blocks i wasted two days so people
really better appreciate the extra
depths i went to the puns
to get this to work i also have to shout
out to tango because i uh i have and
died here i lost some stuff he went
ahead and collected up all my gear so
that i didn't miss out
so
i mean it's quite a long drop now in
theory i have to skydive through things
and then i will plunge into water that
little bit of extra space does make a
difference i'm just not sure whether it
was worth
the nine hours i spent losing my marbles
and it's not even over because now we
need to go into another building time
lapse of making this look a little bit
nicer so yet again let's go and lose
some more marbles i mean i've only got a
few left they're rattling around in
there i wonder i can't see anything as
stupid wall normally i'd say let's go
let's go
we're done but there's something a
little more important that i've just
found an afk oh they're holding a totem
as well it's like they're asking for it
hmm
what can we do
here
as a matter of fact
i actually happen to have
yes i have
i actually have a bunch of obsidian
so i mean it's the oldest trick in the
book but why not
the old obsidian cage there's no easy
way to get out you just gotta kind of
accept your fate i know he's on my team
but you can't afk around me it's just
the rules he's properly afk you know
what let's make this even more
interesting the more time that i have
the more interesting that it gets
i think ren's cottoned onto what's going
on here
just remember this is for doc's own
safety
nothing to do with prankage it's it's
it's for his own good
everyone's
everyone's in on it
we're about to make this
a whole lot more interesting a whole lot
more interesting it's like an unwritten
rule that if you go afk like that you're
kind of fair game we got two layers of
obsidian a layer of lava in between i
guess we'll see how he reacts to this
and it shouldn't be too difficult for
him to get out but it definitely is
going to be a bit of a shock and now
we cap off this obsidian cake
with another layer
mwah the worst rubik's cube you've ever
seen
and i can't actually see that there he
is somewhere inside there doc is gonna
get a nice surprise
from one of his teammates and he won't
even know who did this i'm gonna i'm not
even gonna i'm gonna blame hep stir the
pot a little bit this was this was this
was hep's doing but anyway we just got
out of a time lapse and i got distracted
by the very afk person so i have
completed this
and i've
firmly and i mean firmly only have one
more marble in my possession i have lost
my mind making this stuff
this serious amount of time
and just i don't know like not a lot of
benefit but at least it looks pretty
good compared to how it was
but i think we need to acknowledge
just how insane
24 hours have been on this server so
yesterday
i had just completed the big hole and
look what's popped up a giant maze which
is i've got to say doc not the best
positioning it's kind of raised out off
the ground a little bit odd but i at
least you've decorated it really really
nicely got my mini game popping up ethos
game which i'm not even sure what it is
and a couple other minigames like loads
of minigames have popped up and been
decorated really nicely the only issue
is that the rest of the island looks
like a massive and i mean massive
eyesore the amount of activity around
this area has been insane but i guess it
really does fall to me to try and make
this look a little nicer than a giant
square
scar's made his game over here i don't
know what he's doing but look at this
crazy crazy stuff so i can't wait to see
his episode with that being said there's
a lot to do all work in progress
including mine which we're going to come
back to a little later on because like i
said this place is an eyesore and if you
don't believe me that i've been mining
for 13 hours straight
just look at the
chest of materials that i have i mean
they're all going to be stuck in the
barge but i mean look at this nonsense
it is just
never ending stuff actually struggling
to find free space in it now the reason
i point this out is because it's about
to get worse you see
because this is such an eyesore i'm it's
kind of my responsibility to do
something about it so you see this here
i'm going to
mine all of this back and i'm going to
try and make like a backboard to this
whole thing
just to try and tidy it up a little bit
because it is close to the shopping
district we do want this to look nice
it's just a lot of work and i'm i'm
guessing it's going to be down to me
what on earth are all these shulker
boxes for why is everyone got buckets of
green here sorry did i just say buckets
i think i just invented a new word
box buckets buckets
spot on who's left several boxes of
green come back
come back he's making a bid for it all
right well that's probably one of the
weirder finds of today but either way we
need to get into making this place look
a little nicer i'm hoping some of the
other hermits might help me but i kind
of brought this on myself in all
fairness so for the third time today and
the reason that i am going to call this
episode so i did a little mining on
camera
it's because i've done nothing but mine
on
camera
so i'm gonna say it again let's go
[Applause]
and we are done we've got a nice
backboard to this whole area
i'm gonna say right now that it's not
absolutely perfect but you know what for
the time that i had and the blocks that
i had available i think it's a real
improvement you don't even realize that
the mesa is literally on the other side
of this so i think i think overall
a massive massive success
but there's also been
another success ow you see last episode
i tried to make an airplane in the sky
and it didn't go well just kind of
looked like a floating cylinder so a
friend of corrales is called fifi
actually gave corrales a design to put
in the game and i woke up today and
what there's a there's a fresh
plane
i
i don't know what kind of plane an
amazing plane
this is so much better we gotta go and
have a little look at this
this is so much better
than anything i could have created so
massive thank you to not only corrales
but fifi on his server that went ahead
and made this because i can't believe it
i i really like it looks absolutely
fantastic
and so this is now the launch platform
that you come out of i'll probably add
another one
on this side as well
so you have a couple of options
and i still need to make the rings but
that's the last thing i need to do and
then this game is done so check it out
you gotta fly around and try and get in
as quickly as possible
and i actually need to check
very quickly whether this kills you or
not i haven't actually bothered to see
whether
one block of water is enough i i think
it is
i think one block of water is enough
for you not to die but we're gonna find
out
that doesn't make much sense does it if
this was real life i would be a green
pancake on the floor
so
physics aside
i think this has gone pretty well
you're probably wondering what this
scaffolding is all about well this is me
planning out all of the rings the bit
that you actually have to worry about
flying through
the rings in the skydive and this one
was just to find out where the center is
of the plane
so we can get rid of this one
oh man
oh it's still going
hey it's snowing
well actually this is this is the
closest i'm ever gonna get to snow for
christmas in the uk
yeah it's not quite the same is it
man it's it's still coming
so today is officially the deadline for
the games to be completed we're not
playing them today but they are
completed and we're gonna start
arranging
for everyone else to get involved in the
games this week
and it looks for the most part like
games are pretty much there
from what i can tell most of them are
ready to go maybe scars needs a couple
more minutes on it but overall
i think we're pretty much ready to go
and i might even add a couple of
surprises i'm not entirely sure but i'll
tell you what i've had enough of this
area for a very long time i'm i'm i'm
sapped of energy
i can no longer mine on camera
that took 13 hours that took several
hours i am out i've had enough oh wait i
forgot about the mess
the fruit of my labor is here and i tell
you what i don't know what to do with it
i really don't know what to do with it
it needs to be collected up in a
sensible way i've run out of shulker
boxes you know what that's that that
would be a nice break we're gonna go to
the end
not been to the end in a long time
because i need shulker boxes and i
believe last time i checked
the chest monster was completely empty
yep
wow stock is low
maybe
did did anyone hear
that open
i def i 100
heard
one of these barrels open is there a
villager in here
so many animals have been stuck in here
what on earth
there's a villager in here i can i can
hear them
why hello there how long have you been
hiding in here oh my goodness it's from
all the way back
you have saved me this is from all the
way back during the mayor campaign
when everyone was running for mayor
you've been stuck under there
for like eight months
and you smell like you've been stuck
under there for eight months that
opening of the barrel was your way of
saying oh please please help me well i
have liberated you from your cage and
unfortunately
i must liberate you
from your head
or rather liberate your head from your
body we've had a particular issue with
lag in the in the shopping district
recently so all of those stray mobs
they've got to go
but i do feel kind of guilty now
actually because that was uh the lone
survivor right i'm all ready for a
little bit of solo end busting
just realized i don't actually know
where the end portal is at all
but i have just found a christmas
district
we are 100 gonna visit that
oh my goodness is that what i think it
is
very whoa
check it out i knew they'd made an
advent calendar but i didn't realize how
big it was
this is enormous
doesn't that just fill you with nice
warm fuzzy feelings i wonder which
number is for me
anyway i just wanted to check this out
what an amazing build and what a
snowball
no but let's not get distracted because
we need to try and find this end portal
turns out it's down here and i've never
actually used one of these guys before
striders
i can't actually figure out what these
look like it somehow
both resembles a jelly bean
and a 40 year old man
hey
now we're wobbling this is not the most
efficient way to travel i believe but
it's certainly pretty fun ah we're here
man it took me like 20 minutes just to
find this place
whoa
that is bright
okay so i feel like we're kind of ready
let's go and get ourselves a few shulker
boxes uh it looks like this end city has
been more than just raided
it's just
gone
straight up gone so while we're looking
for a real end city i need to tell you
about something really strange
that happened
while while i was on the server but i
wasn't properly recording so i was
making the turf war sign and etho comes
up to me and he says like do you see oh
there's an end city no he didn't say
there's an end city he said
take a look at this
and i was like what
and look at this footage the man
is i've never seen this bug before i've
been playing minecraft many years and
this is a very strange bug
he is constantly stuck in riptide and
just spinning
he could
crouch while spinning fly while spinning
do anything while spinning i would i
would i would love to to know how to
make this bug work but i i just thought
i had to share that
so we are here and we are here to
collect these guys for our shulker boxes
what is going on
oh
some nice diamonds and an elytra
now hopefully i won't have to spend too
much time here but at some point i
really need to do like a proper end
busting session
okay one end city down
and nearly a stack of shulker boxes i
don't think that's even enough i think
i've got to keep going
how many endermen can i make angry
hello
oh i guess they can't see me from here
can you see me oh yeah you see me
this is a terrible idea i don't want to
alarm anyone but i can't see where i'm
flying
it's not loading finally another end
city
i've been flying for like
10 million years and that's not an
exaggeration i never exaggerate oh
someone's already been here
it's like finding out that that slice of
pizza that you left in the fridge
it's like someone someone's taken it and
eaten it there's nothing you can do
about it but you're still angry
can't believe they ate my pizza
if this one's raided we're calling it
quits looking good so far
potentially
yeah
there we go
a couple more of these at the end of
this one we should have enough
to be able to take the fruit of our
labor from earlier in today's episode
and organize it and get it out of the
way because there is that's just an
obscene there's probably more stuff
where i just did that mining project
than my in my entire base and i think
that might be a fact all right let's get
out of here i think that's more than
enough shulker boxes i thought i would
enjoy today's end bus but i must admit i
did not
it took me a really long time to find
end cities that weren't raided and it
was uh not quite as exciting as i
imagined now we need to do is find one
of those ender pearl flavored tic tacs
to get out of here
i think that's the best description of
these i've ever come up with because
that flavor right there i would describe
that as ender pearl and we go
back
straight back
i don't think we could have taken a more
direct route okay this may take so long
that i may even need to i may even need
to time-lapse sorting out items
that's how many there are
this is gonna be
not fun
okay
let's get this let's get this done
and check it out
pretty much
spotless and clean
i'll let you decide in the comments how
long you thought that would take because
i bet none of you will actually guess
how much time we waste
searching through chests and stuff
despite my complaining about that for
the pretty much the entire episode we
did get our game pretty much finished
we'll have to do
probably just the the rings at the start
of the next episode give it a test and
hopefully next episode will actually get
people to play in the real thing the the
mini games begin
however
despite me complaining about the many
many hours almost a day that i spent
mining stuff check it out i have
tidied it up and put it all in the barge
now i started this whole thing a while
ago the second layer of the barge but
this is selling it by the box and you
can see we got stone six six diamonds
per box so that's a mega deal a mega
deal
that is
that is amazing both cobblestone and
stone six diamonds a box but then i
looked at
this like there was loads of boxes
missing and i looked and
people have been buying it i know it's a
good deal but
what
that is they basically bought all of the
stone all the cobblestones so i think
we're on to a winner here there is a
serious amount of stock that has gone
into this now i have done slightly more
nine diamonds for andesite granite
and for diorite
as well as mixed terracotta like i said
there is so much stock here if all of
this sells or sells even a little bit i
am in for some major major profits
another casual 18 diamond blocks
but it doesn't end there
because there are even more sales it's a
slow burner but it does so well and with
that i think i'm gonna have to call it
a day more than a day it's been a very
long week in fact i'm so tired this
episode has taken it out of me so if you
don't mind
i'm gonna go to bed
and i shall see you
in the next episode where we will
conclude
the turf
you